“山洞帮”
布屈卡西狄和日舞小子率领的山洞帮 现已覆灭
但他们曾经横行西部
保罗·纽曼
罗伯特·雷德福
凯瑟琳·罗斯
虎豹小霸 王
编剧：威廉姆·高德曼
制片：约翰·福尔曼
导演：乔治·罗伊·希尔
根据真实故事改编
停业
- 晚安 派特     - 晚安
- Good night, Pat. - Good night.
- 出什么事了？这家老银行过去很漂亮   - 老是被人抢劫
- What happened? Old bank was beautiful. - People kept robbing it.
为了漂亮总是要付出点儿代价的
It's a small price to pay for beauty.
再给我一张
Hit me.
再来
Again.
爆了！
Bust!
可以赊点帐吗 马孔先生？
Give me credit, Mr Macon?
你知道我的规矩 汤姆
You know my rules, Tom.
噢 看来你又把他们都赢光了 伙计
Well, looks like you just about cleaned everybody out, fella.
自从你做庄之后就一手都没输过
You haven't lost a hand since you got the deal.
你赢牌的秘诀是什么？
What's the secret of your success?
祷告
Prayer.
那就我们两个人玩一把吧
Let's just you and me play.
再给我一张
Hit it.
爆了！
Bust!
耶 你是个玩牌的高手 伙计
Yeah. You're a hell of a card player, fella.
我知道 因为我也是个玩牌的高手
I know, cos I'm a hell of a card player.
而我甚至都没看出你是怎么出千的
And I can't even spot how you're cheating.
把钱留下 你走吧
The money stays and you go.
噢 看来我们在这儿有点不受欢迎啊
Well, we seem to be a little short on brotherly love around here.
- 要是你跟他是一伙儿的 你最好也给我出去   - 我们这就走
- If you're with him, you better get out of here. - We're on our way.
- 走吧     - 我才没有出千
- Come on. - I wasn't cheating.
- 走吧！   - 我没有！
- Come on! - I wasn't!
你会死的 要是那样的话 你们两个都要死
You can die. For that matter, you can both die.
- 听见了吗？   - 要是他请我们留下来 我们就走
- Hear that? - If he invites us to stay, we'll go.
- 我们反正也要走   - 他一定要请我们留下
- We were gonna leave anyway. - He's gotta invite us to stick around.
他会朝你拔枪的 他已经准备那么做了 你不知道他拔枪的速度有多快
He'll draw on you. He's ready. You don't know how fast he is.
- 我已经走下坡了 你也可能一样   - 我就想听这个
- I'm over the hill, but it can happen to you. - That's just what I wanna hear.
每天你都在变老 知道吗 那就是规律
Every day you get older. Now, that's a law.
你能考虑下求我们留下来吗？
What would you think about maybe asking us to stick around?
- 什么？   - 就算不是真心话也行
- What? - You don't have to mean it.
只要求我们留下来 我向你保证...
Just ask us to stick around. I promise you...
我可帮不了你 圣丹斯
I can't help you, Sundance.
我说你出千的时候不知道你就是圣丹斯小子
I didn't know you were the Sundance Kid when I said you were cheating.
要是我向你拔枪的话 你就会杀了我
If I draw on you, you'll kill me.
很有可能
There's that possibility.
不 你这是自寻死路 那你为什么还不求我们留下来呢？
No. You'd be killing yourself. So why don't you just invite us to stick around?
现在 你就可以求我们
Now, you can do it.
这不难 来吧
And easy. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
为什么你们不留下来呢？
Why don't you stick around?
谢谢 不过我们要走了
Thanks, but we gotta get going.
嘿 小子
Hey, Kid.
嘿 小子！你究竟有多厉害？
Hey, Kid! How good are ya?
就像我跟你说的那样 走下坡路了
Like I been telling you, over the hill.
伙计 每次我看见那个山洞 就像是第一次看到它那样
Boy, every time I see Hole in the Wall again, it's like seeing it fresh for the first time.
于是我每次都会突然问自己这样一个问题
And every time that happens I keep asking myself the same question.
“我怎么会这么蠢还要回到这儿来？”
How can I be so damn stupid as to keep coming back here?
- 那你这次是主意？   - 波利维亚
- What's your idea this time? - Bolivia.
- 波利维亚是什么？   - 波利维亚 那是个国家 笨蛋
- What's Bolivia? - Bolivia. That's a country, stupid.
在中美或是南美 反正就在这其中之一
In Central or South America. One or the other.
为什么我们不直接去墨西哥？
Why don't we just go to Mexico instead?
到墨西哥只会让人吃苦头 还不如留在这儿
Cos all they got in Mexico is sweat. There's too much of that here.
要是我们在加利福尼亚淘金潮的时候就开始干的话 我们得去什么地方？
If we'd been in business in the California gold rush, where'd we have gone?
- 加利福尼亚 是吗？   - 是的
- California, right? - Right.
我说玻利维亚的时候 你想到的就是加利福尼亚
So when I say Bolivia, you just think California.
你都不会相信他们都在那儿的地下找到了什么
You wouldn't believe what they're finding in the ground down there.
银矿 金矿 锡矿
Silver mines, gold mines, tin mines.
工资如此之丰厚 我们偷走它们的时候还会把自己累得够呛
Payrolls so heavy we'd strain ourselves stealing them.
你继续胡思乱想吧 布奇 你就在行那个！
You just keep thinking, Butch. That's what you're good at!
伙计 我有着世上其他人所没有的洞察力
Boy, I got vision and the rest of the world wears bifocals.
嗨 万事通 你在做什么？
Hi, News. Whatcha doing?
噢 你好 布奇 没做什么
Oh, howdy, Butch. Nothing.
没做什么
Nothing.
你好 圣丹斯
Howdy, Sundance.
噢 你当然在做什么 你在做什么东西 是什么东西？
Well, you sure are. You're doing something. What?
只是准备抢劫联合太平洋铁路公司的快车 布奇 这就是我们想做的
Just fixing to rob the Union Pacific Flyer, Butch. That's all we had in mind.
你们完全没按我说的做
You fellas got everything I told you all wrong.
当然 我们也许会去抢劫那辆快车
True, we might hit the Flyer,
不过就算我们要抢 也不是这一趟 而是下一趟-返程的那趟
but even if we do, it won't be this run. It'll be the next one - the return.
- 圣丹斯同我已经去看过那家银行了   - 我们不打劫银行
- Sundance and me been checking the banks. - No banks.
什么？
What?
我们打劫快车 布奇
The Flyer, Butch.
伙计们 再怎么说 银行也比火车好抢
Fellas, bad as they are, banks are better than trains.
银行不会跑 它们就在那儿 你知道钱就在里边
They don't move. They stay put. You know the money's in there.
- 我走的时候已经下令了   - 我已经下了新的命令
- When I left I gave orders. - New orders been given.
噢 我才是这里的老大 哈维
Well, I run things here, Harvey.
过去是你
Used to you did.
现在是我了
Me now.
这跟你没关系！
This don't concern you!
- 告诉他别插手   - 噢 他总是那样我行我素的
- You tell him to stay out. - Well, he goes his own way like always.
你们都是怎么回事？
What's the matter with you guys?
我来这儿的时候 你们甚至连个团伙都算不上 是我把你们组织起来的!
When I came here, you weren't even a gang. I formed ya!
- 谁说的？   - 噢 把剪报念给他们听听 万事通
- Who says? - Well, read them a clipping, News.
- 哪份？   - 随便哪份！
- Which one? - Any of them!
这是盐湖城先锋报的
This one here's from the Salt Lake Herald.
- “布奇 卡西迪率领的山洞帮...”   - 布奇 卡西迪率领的山洞帮-说的是我！
- "Butch Cassidy's Hole in the Wall Gang..." - Butch Cassidy's gang - that's me!
你们要让哈维给你们出计划吗？要他替你们想吗？要他替你们做主吗？
You want Harvey to do your planning? To do your thinking? To run things?
- “...他们无法无天...”   - 现在闭嘴 万事通！
- "...outlaws with them on..." - Shut up now, News!
我还没读到精彩的地方呢 布奇
Not till I get to the good part, Butch.
“据悉一同参与抢劫的有扁鼻子卡瑞和万事通卡维”
"Known to have participated in the holdup are Flat Nose Curry and News Carver."
我就喜欢在报上读到自己的名字 布奇
I just love to read my name in the paper, Butch.
OK 那么我们就忘了洛根想做老大的事了 OK 扁鼻子？
OK, so we forget about Logan taking over. OK, Flat Nose?
你一直都说我们中任何人都可以向你挑战
You always said any one of us could challenge you.
- 那是因为我想没人会那样做   - 你想错了 布奇
- It's cos I figured no one would do it. - Figured wrong, Butch.
你们不会想让洛根做老大吧！
You guys can't want Logan!
至少他和我们在一起 布奇 你经常都不在
At least he's with us, Butch. You've been spending a lot of time gone.
- 一切都不同了   - 用枪还是用刀？
- Cos everything's different. - Guns or knives?
- 现在没以前好过了 你们得好好考虑一下   - 用枪还是用刀？！
- It's harder now. You gotta plan more. - Guns or knives?!
- 都不要   - 快选一个！
- Neither. - Pick!
我不想向你开枪 哈维
I don't wanna shoot with you, Harvey.
不管你怎么说 布奇
Anything you say, Butch.
说不定可以趁这个机会赚一把
Maybe there's a way to make a profit in this.
我赌洛根赢
Bet on Logan.
- 我会的 可谁会买你赢呢？   - 圣丹斯
- I would, but who'd bet on you? - Sundance,
等我们决斗完 要是他死了 还是欢迎你留下来
when we're done, if he's dead, you're welcome to stay.
听着 我并不想被人当成输不起 不过等决斗结束后 要是我死了 就杀了他
Listen, I don't mean to be a sore loser, but when it's done, if I'm dead, kill him.
我很乐意
Love to.
不 不 还没呢 我和哈维先把规矩订清楚
No, no, not yet. Not until me and Harvey get the rules straightened out.
规矩？用刀决斗还要什么规矩？没有规矩！
Rules? In a knife fight? No rules!
要是没有规矩的话 就开始吧 谁来数 1 2 3 开始
If there ain't no rules, let's start. Someone count 1, 2, 3, go.
1 2 3 开始！
1, 2, 3, go!
我刚才绝对一直都在支持你 布奇
I was really rooting for you, Butch.
噢 谢谢 扁鼻子
Well, thank you, Flat Nose.
真是患难见真情
That's what sustained me in my time of trouble.
嘿 怎会想去抢劫快车？
Hey, what's this about the Flyer?
哈维说我们往返两趟都要抢
Harvey said we'd hit it both this run and the return.
之前还从没有人抢过快车 不管我们头一次抢到多少
Nobody's done that to the Flyer before. No matter how much we got the first time,
他们会认为返程的时候不会有事就会在上边装上钱的
they'd figure the return was safe and load it up with money.
- 那是哈维想出来的吗？！   - 是的 老大 是他想出来的
- Harvey thought of that?! - Yes, sir. He did.
噢 我来告诉你们吧 我们确实就是要那样做
Well, I'll tell you something. That's exactly what we're gonna do.
- 停车   - 停在哪儿？
- Stop it! - Where?
就在前面那儿
Up ahead there.
我打赌那是就是老布奇他本人！
Bet that's old Butch himself!
别动
Hold it there.
- 我只是想看看   - 你干嘛不把孩子们带来一块儿看呢？
- I just thought I'd watch. - Bring the kids, why don't you?
别把你们的脑袋探出来
Stick your heads in.
你们要是不开门的话 你们就会被炸飞
You'll get yourself blown up, you don't open that door.
我是为联合太平洋铁路公司的EH 哈里曼工作的 我不能那么做...
I can't do that on account of I work for EH Harriman of the Union Pacific Railroad...
别说什么EH 哈里曼的员工了 把门打开！
Shut up about that EH Harriman stuff and open the door!
- 怎么了？   - 我们遇到个爱国者
- What's going on? - We got a patriot in there.
- OK 动手吧 万事通   - 那是伍德考克 他相当忠心
- OK, go ahead, News. - That's Woodcock. He's awful dedicated.
- 伍德考克！   - 什么事 老大？
- Woodcock! - Yes, sir.
你知道我们是谁吗？
You know who we are?
您是山洞帮的卡西迪先生 我知道
You're the Hole in the Wall Gang, Mr Cassidy. I understand.
不过您要知道这份工作是联合太平洋公司的EH 哈里曼先生亲自给我的
But you gotta understand Mr EH Harriman himself of the Union Pacific give me this job.
- 我必须尽力做好 您明白吗？   - 那应该不包括让你自己送命吧！
- I've gotta do my best, don't you see? - That don't include getting yourself killed!
- 炸药准备好了   - EH 哈里曼先生相信...
- Dynamite's ready. - Mr EH Harriman had the confidence...
要么打开门要么我们就炸开！你认为EH 哈里曼会为你送命吗？
Open the door or that's it! Do you think EH Harriman would get himself killed for you?
伍德考克？
Woodcock?
我是为联合太平洋铁路公司的EH 哈里曼先生工作 他委托我...
I work for Mr EH Harriman of the Union Pacific Railroad, and he entrusted me...
嘿 伍德考克 嘿 伍德考克 你没事吧？
Hey, Woodcock. Hey, Woodcock, you all right?
嘿
Hey.
不管哈里曼付你多少都不够
Whatever Harriman's paying you ain't enough.
这里的钱完全不值得抢 布奇
There ain't what I'd call a fortune in there, Butch.
噢 我们这不过是刚开始 这才是最重要的
Well, just so we come out ahead. That's the main thing.
我相信大家都听说了 山洞帮 在我们镇外抢劫了快车
The Hole in the Wall Gang, I guess you heard, robbed the Flyer outside our town,
我们有责任赶到那里并追捕他们
so that makes it our responsibility to get out there and get after them.
现在 你们得骑上自己的马
Now, you're gonna have to bring your own horses.
你们有多少人自己带的有枪？
How many of you can bring your own guns?
嗯 很好 有多少人需要我提供枪的？
Yeah, well, how many of you are going to want me to supply you with guns?
噢...行了 我想我们应该有所行动 不是吗？
Well... Come on, now. I think it's up to us to do something, don't you?
为什么？他们说不定已经在回山洞的半路上了
Why? They're probably halfway to Hole in the Wall already.
所以我们才要尽快出发啊
That's just exactly why we have got to hurry.
要是我们现在就上马去追他们 说不定我们还能追得上
If we get mounted up right now and get after them, maybe we could head them off.
追上他们？你疯了吗？要是我们真追上了 他们会杀了我们的
Head them off? You crazy? We did that, they'd kill us.
噢 我可不认为我们就这么躺着让他们逃走了...
Well, I don't think we want to lie down and just let them get away with this...
伙计 我刚才真是细细品味了一把！
Boy, I just eat this up with a spoon!
行了 你们两个 我要你们出席我的聚会
All right, you two. I want you at my party.
- 什么聚会？   - 我的钢琴师要走了
- What party? - I'm losing my piano player.
他就要去打仗了
He's going off to fight the war.
- 打什么仗？   - 同西班牙人打的那场
- What war? - The war with the Spanish.
“想想缅因州”
"Remember the Maine."
- 谁会忘了呢？   - 我要为他送行 来吧
- Who can forget it? - I'm giving him a send-off, so come on.
再见 多莉 我必须离开你...
Goodbye, Dolly, I must leave you...
我还是个孩子的时候 我就总想着能够成为一名英雄
When I was a kid, I always thought I was gonna grow up to be a hero.
- 噢 已经太迟了   - 你说这话什么意思？你没必要那么说的
- Well, it's too late now. - What'd you say that for? You didn't have to.
你们要我去的话 就算只有我一个人 我也要同山洞帮战斗 该死的 我没关系
You want me to go, I'll go all alone and fight the Hole in the Wall Gang. Hell, that's fine with me.
你们想让你们的孩子们知道是你们让我一个人去的 我没关系！
And you want your kids to know that you let me do that, that's fine with me!
可我不认为那就是你们想的吧
But I don't think that's what you want.
对吧？
Is it?
我们为什么不入伍？去同西班牙人打仗
Why don't we enlist? Go fight the Spanish.
你还有我都去打仗
You and me in the war.
我们有很多的优势 经验 成熟 领导力
We got a lot of things going for us. Experience, maturity, leadership.
我打赌我们都会成为军官
I bet we end up officers.
我将会成为帕克少校
I'd be Major Parker.
帕克？
Parker?
没错 那是我的真名
Yeah, that's my real name.
- 罗伯特 勒罗伊 帕克   - 不是开玩笑的？
- Robert LeRoy Parker. - No fooling?
是的
Yeah.
- 我叫朗堡夫   - 不是开玩笑的？
- Mine's Longbaugh. - No fooling?
- 朗什么？   - 哈里 朗堡夫
- Long what? - Harry Longbaugh.
这么说你就是朗堡夫少校了 你觉得怎么样？
So you'd be Major Longbaugh. Whaddaya say?
你接着胡思乱想吧 布奇 你就在行这个！
You just keep thinking, Butch. That's what you're good at!
可你们不是被吓坏了！不是的 先生！你们尊重我而我也同样尊重你们！
But you're not frantic! No, sir! You have got respect for me and I have got respect for you!
因此我才成为你们的警长！这就是为什么你还有你还有你要同我一同出发！
That is why I'm your marshal! And that is why you and you and you are riding with me!
我说的对吗？
Am I right?
怎么样？你们有什么话？
Well? Whaddaya say?
我要说的是：
I say this:
我要说 女士们先生们
I say, ladies and gentlemen,
男孩儿还有女孩儿 朋友还有敌人
boys and girls, friends and enemies,
- 一起见证未来！   - 什么未来？
- meet the future! - The future what?
这是西方世界最为先进的交通工具
The future mode of transportation for this western world.
听着 我可不想对这个小机器夸大其词
Now, I'm not gonna make a lot of extravagant claims for this little machine.
但可以肯定的是 它能让你的生活变得更好 就是这样！
Sure, it'll change your whole life for the better, but that's all!
你知道自己在干什么吗？
What do you think you're doing?
你把人都召集到这儿了 我只是觉得我可以顺便卖点儿东西
You got the crowd together. Just thought I'd do a little selling.
- 我正在召集一支民防队！   - 我就再说一会儿
- I'm trying to raise a posse here! - Got a short presentation.
马已经过时了！你们会发现这东西绝对值得购买
The horse is dead! You'll see this item sells itself.
你们是要继续听他讲下去呢 还是跟我去？
Are you going to listen to him, or come with me?
布奇 芬妮叫你去参加她的派对 现在就去
Butch, Fanny says for you to come in to her party, right now.
比养马的费用更低 不需要喂燕麦 不会有排泄物 不会蹬腿 更不会自己跑不见...
Cheaper than a horse to keep. No oats, no mess, no kicks, no running away...
好吧
Well,
我想我也该装上马鞍去找个女人了
I think I'll get saddled up and go looking for a woman.
祝你猎艳顺利
Good hunting.
这花不了几天
Shouldn't take more than a couple of days.
我又不挑剔
I'm not picky.
只要她聪明 漂亮...
As long as she's smart, pretty...
甜美
and sweet.
文雅还有...温柔还有...
And gentle and... tender and...
有教养还有
refined and
可爱还有...天真...
lovely and... carefree...
继续吧 女士教师
Keep going, teacher lady.
没事 别管我 你继续吧
It's OK. Don't mind me. Keep on going.
把头发放下来
Let down your hair.
甩动你的头
Shake your head.
- 知道我希望什么吗？   - 什么？
- Know what I wish? - What?
那就是你可以准时来这儿一次！
That once you'd get here on time!
你是我的 埃塔 佩雷斯
You are mine, Etta Place.
我的！
Mine!
你听见了吗？
You hear me?
我的！全是我的！
Mine! All mine!
你柔软 洁白的身体是我的
Your soft, white flesh is mine.
柔软
Soft.
洁白
White.
见证未来！
Meet the future!
- 你知道你在做什么吗？   - 理论上是的
- Do you know what you're doing? - Theoretically.
别拿铁铲打你的母亲
Don't ever hit your mother with a shovel
这样只会使她的脑子变得迟钝！
It leaves a dull impression on her mind!
雨不断落在我的头上
Raindrops keep falling on my head
就像是那些脚对床来说都显得太大的人
And just like the guy whose feet are too big for his bed
什么鞋都不会合适
Nothing seems to fit, those
雨不断落在我的头上 它们不断的落下
Raindrops are falling on my head, they keep falling
我是我开始同太阳说话
So I just did me some talking to the sun
我说自己不喜欢他做事的方式
And I said I didn't like the way he got things done
我做事的时候他却睡了
Sleeping on the job, those
雨不断落在我的头上 它们不断的落下
Raindrops are falling on my head, they keep falling
可我唯一知道的就是
But there's one thing I know
它们只让我变得忧郁
The blues they send to meet me
这不能摧垮我
Won't defeat me
这不会持续太久 直到幸福张开双臂向我走来
It won't be long till happiness steps up to greet me
雨不断落在我的头上
Raindrops keep falling on my head
可那不意味着我的眼圈就快要红了
But that doesn't mean my eyes will soon be turning red
这不是为我自己而哭的 因为
Crying's not for me, cos
我从没有停止过对雨的抱怨
I'm never gonna stop the rain by complaining
因为我是自由的
Because I'm free
没什么好担心的
Nothing's worrying me
雨不断落在我的头上
Raindrops are falling on my head
可那不意味着我的眼圈就快要红了
But that doesn't mean my eyes will soon be turning red
这不是为我自己而哭的 因为
Crying's not for me, cos
我从没有停止过对雨的抱怨
I'm never gonna stop the rain by complaining
因为我是自由的
Because I'm free
没什么好担心的
Nothing's worrying
我
Me
你是为了快车的事来找他的吧？
You've come to get him for the Flyer?
你能相信我已经破产了吗？
Can you believe I'm broke already?
- 为什么总是没有钱 布奇？   - 天 我发誓 埃塔 我不知道
- Why is there never any money, Butch? - Hell, I swear, Etta, I don't know.
我这辈子都像条狗那样忙碌着 可我还是一分钱也存不下来
I've been working like a dog all my life and I can't get a penny ahead.
圣丹斯说那是因为你太容易花钱 总是花很多去度假
Sundance says it's cos you're a soft touch, always taking expensive vacations,
请每个人喝酒 而且你还滥赌
buying drinks for everyone, and you're a rotten gambler.
嗯 也许跟这个也有关系吧！
Well, that might have something to do with it!
布奇？
Butch?
你有没有想过要是我先遇到你 我们两个会在一起？
D'you ever wonder if I'd met you first, we'd been the ones to get involved?
我们已经在一起了 埃塔 你还不知道吗？
We are involved, Etta. Don't you know that?
你正坐在我的自行车上 在一些阿拉伯国家里 这就相当于你嫁给我了
You're riding on my bicycle. In some Arabian countries that's the same as being married.
嘿
Hey.
- 你在做什么？   - 偷你的女人
- What're you doing? - Stealing your woman.
带她走吧 带她走吧
Take her. Take her.
你真是个浪漫的浑蛋 我会如你所愿的
You're a romantic bastard. I'll give you that.
- OK 把它打开   - 我为EH 哈里曼先生工作...
- OK, open up in there. - I work for Mr EH Harriman of the Union...
- 嘿 伍德考克   - 布奇？
- Hey, Woodcock! - Butch?
- 你没事吧？   - 噢 还算好吧
- You OK? - Well, sort of.
嘿 那就太好了 让我看看你
Hey, that's wonderful. Let's take a look at ya.
这次 布奇 这次你不会认为我是故意做戏的吧 你该更敬佩我了
Now, Butch, you gotta have more respect for me than to think I'd fall for a stunt like that.
- 你不会又想被炸飞吧？   - 布奇 要知道如果这是我自己的钱
- You can't wanna get blown up again? - Butch, you know that if it were my money,
要是被抢的话我只愿意让你抢
there is nobody that I would rather have steal it than you.
可是我仍是在为联合太平洋铁路公司的EH 哈里曼先生工作
But I am still in the employ of Mr EH Harriman of the Union Pacific Railroad.
- 开车！   - 回到里面去 女士
- Start this train! - Get back inside, lady.
噢 我可不怕你 我什么都不怕
Oh, I'm not afraid of you. I'm not afraid of anything.
我是个女人 我都做祖母了 我有权利
I'm a grandmother and a female, and I've got my rights.
- 我们没时间跟她废话了   - 你可以吓住其他人 可吓不到我！
- We've got no time for this. - You can bull all the others, but not me!
我已经打败了[戒掉了]威士忌还有赌博！我当然也能够打败你！
I've fought whiskey and gambling! I can certainly fight you!
我们没时间跟她废话了！
We got no time for this!
- 把枪放下 圣丹斯   - 别管她了！
- Put down the gun, Sundance. - Let go!
- 你们打算把她怎么样？   - 这是你逼我的
- What you gonna do to her? - Whatever you force me to.
放开她 你们不就是要钱吗 钱就在这里
Leave her alone. You're after the money, and the money's in here.
我所希望的就是有人把车开走 有人吗！求你们了！
All I want is for somebody to start this train. Somebody! Please!
- 把门打开否则就跟她说再见吧！   - 我们在天上的父[背诵主祷文]
- Open up or tell her goodbye! - Our Father, who art in heaven,
愿人都尊你的名为圣
hallowed be thy name.
愿你的国降临
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
愿你的旨意行在地上 如同行在天上
on earth, as it is in heaven.
我该怎样向不幸的哈里曼先生解释？
What am I gonna tell poor Mr Harriman?
伍德考克 你为什么要这么做？
Woodcock, what d'you have to do something like that for?
噢 布奇 上一个被你轻易的就炸开了所以我做了一些改进
Well, Butch, you blew the last one so easy I just had to do something.
炸药给我 再多来点
Give me that, and get some more.
都拿来！
A lot more!
噢 这样应该没问题
Well, that oughta do it.
你认为炸药够了吗 布奇？
Think you used enough dynamite there, Butch?
这他妈怎么回事？
What the hell is that?
不管他们是干什么的 我都不想遇到他们
Whatever they're selling, I don't want it.
你们能别管它了吗！
Will you leave it!
快走！
Come on!
- 嘿 布奇   - 什么？
- Hey, Butch. - What?
他们都是些好手
They're very good.
分开逃！
Split up!
- 他们有多少人在追我们？   - 全部都在追我们
- How many of them are following us? - All of them.
全部？为什么不追那些家伙？！
All of them? What's the matter with those guys?!
我想我们甩掉他们了 你认为我们甩掉他们了吗？
I think we lost them. D'you think we lost them?
- 还没有   - 我也是这么想
- No. - Neither do I.
- 笑脸在哪儿？   - 在里边 有什么事吗？
- Where's Sweetface? - Just inside. Trouble?
听着 你这个糟老头 我知道你是个骗子 可谁能看得出来呢？
Listen, you dirty old man, I know you're a lying thief, but who'd know it to look at ya?
快到前边去 就说你5分钟前看到我们从镇里出去了
Get out front fast. You seen us ride through town five minutes ago.
要办好了 我会好好的赏你的
You do this right, I'll get you an old dog to kick.
给你 9号房 就在最楼上
Here, room nine. The top of the stairs.
我最喜欢了
My beloved's proud
嘿 你就这么盯着窗外都快把我逼疯了
Hey, you're driving me crazy staring out the window like that.
我向你发誓笑脸绝对能轻松解决的
I swear to you Sweetface can handle it easy.
他没胆子出卖我 他相当怕我
He wouldn't dare louse me up, he's that scared of me.
阿格妮丝就盯着望着窗外的你 你这样我怎么才能让她注意到我？
How can I give Agnes the concentration she deserves with you looking out the window?
布奇 你说得还真有点道理 你知道吗？
Butch, you're really something, you know that?
你还能看得仔细一点儿么 阿格妮丝？
Could you be a bit more specific, Agnes?
布奇！
Butch!
OK 笑脸 给他们一个迷人的笑容
OK, Sweetface, give them a nice smile.
快点
Come on.
噢 这真的太感人了
Oh, that's a nice touch.
你知道吗 我发誓 要是他告诉我我10分钟前从镇里出去了 我都会信的
You know, I swear, if he told me I rode out of town ten minutes ago, I'd believe him.
然后他们就会追出去的
And there they go.
不 不 不 别让我留下
No, no, no. Don't ask me to stay.
你是我所认识的唯一真正的男人 你该知道的 布奇？
You're the only real man I ever met. You know that, Butch?
不是因为你对人们出手大方
It's notjust cos of all that money you got to spend on people.
而是因为你本身 你总是关心我是开心还是不开心
It's you. The way you're always looking to see am I happy or not.
有很多女孩儿 她们想和你在一起也许只是想
A lot of the other girls, they might want you just for
当你有很多钱可以花的时候可以得到一点儿
when you got lots of money to spend on people.
可我 我...
Me, I...
我不在乎什么衣服 金钱 或者珠宝还有毛皮
I don't care about clothes and money and jewels and furs.
那样的东西 大多数女孩儿都喜欢的 可我从来都不
Things like that. Lots of the other girls do, but I never did.
我常说“阿格妮丝...”
I always said "Agnes..."
别动！
Don't move!
站起来 把手举起来
Stand up. Put your hands up.
举高一点
Higher!
现在转身...
Now turn around and...
把我们的马带过来
Get our horses and come on back here.
出去 出去
Get outta here. Get outta here.
出去！
Get out!
快！都出去 你们这些愚蠢的畜生！
Go on! Get outta here, you fatheaded beast!
- 快点！   - 你们这些愚蠢的畜生 别叫
- Come on! - You're the fatheaded beast. Quit shouting.
伙计 很明显有人训练过它们
Boy, somebody sure trained them.
走哪边？
Which way?
无所谓 我早就不知道我们是在哪儿了
It doesn't matter. I don't know where we've been and I've just been there.
他们追不上我们 我们安全了
They can't follow us. We're safe.
你真的这么认为吗？
You really think so?
要是你这么认为我也觉得是吧
I will if you will.
你认为我们这么看着有多久了？
How long you figure we been watching?
噢 就一会儿吧
Oh, a while.
你还要多久才确定他们没有追我们了？
How long before you figure they're not after us?
再过一会儿吧
A while longer.
你怎么这么多话？
How come you're so talkative?
应该是天生的吧 我想
Just naturally blabby, I guess.
自从我不再偷牛之后很久没这么长时间的骑马了
I haven't done so much riding since I quit rustling.
那真是个相当惨的职业 从黄昏一直到黎明 不能睡觉 吃的东西也都臭了
That's a miserable occupation. Dusk to dawn, no sleep, rotten food.
嘿？
Hey?
我看见了
I see it.
火堆 你觉得呢？
Torches, you think?
也许是 也可能是灯笼
Maybe. Maybe lanterns.
他们正在追踪我们
They're following our path.
而且一点儿都没跟错
Dead on it.
我都做不到 你能做的到吗？他们究竟是怎么做到的？！
I couldn't do that. Could you do that? How can they do that?!
这些都什么人？
Who are those guys?
- 你确定这能行吗？   - 可以的
- Sure it'll work? - It'll work.
- 你之前也是这么说笑脸的！   - 这能行的
- That's what you said about Sweetface! - This'll work.
只要他们分开 我们就干掉他们 没问的 对吧？
Once they divide up, we take them. No trouble. Right?
也许吧
Maybe.
伙计 你可是个枪手 你还是个该死的悲观主义者
Boy, for a gunman, you're one hell of a pessimist.
他们应该很快就到我们分开的地方了
They ought to get to where we split up anytime.
他们就快到了
They're just about there.
你认为追我们的会有多少人？
How many of them you think'll come our way?
我希望我们也有来复枪 我是说 他们有[射程 精度上来复枪都优于手枪]
I wish we had rifles. I mean, they got rifles.
不过我们可以出其不意 对吧？
But we got surprise on our side, right?
嗯 到目前为止他们都是按照我们想的那样在行动
Well, so far they're doing what we want.
你认为我们该从上面那个地方干掉他们吗？
You think we ought to take them from up here?
小子...听着 这种事你比我懂得多了
Kid... look, you know this work better than I do.
是上边那里动手好还是下边那里动手好 就是靠近小路那里？
Is it best here or maybe down there, closer to the trail?
该死！
Dammit!
他们没有走小路
They're not going for it.
这都什么人啊？
Who are those guys?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 我不知道   - 我们得做点什么让他们知道我们的厉害
- I don't know! - We gotta do something and shake them.
不管现在你想出来什么主意我都没意见 不过重要的是 赶紧想出来！
Whatever it is that you come up with is fine with me. But whatever it is, it better be now!
- 雷...   - 你在这儿做什么？
- Ray... - What're you doing?
- 别动 别紧张 雷   - 你他妈什么意思 叫我别紧张？！
- Hold on. Easy, Ray. - What the hell do you mean, take it easy?!
- 你说过你绝不会再到我的地盘上来   - 我们没有 雷 我们没有！
- You said you'd never come to my territory. - We haven't, Ray. We haven't!
即便我们过去是朋友我也不能让你闯进来
Just cos we were friendly doesn't allow you to break in.
要是被发现我们曾在一起我要怎么办？
What would happen to me if we was to be seen together?
我已经老得找不到别的工作了！
I'm too old to hunt up anotherjob!
你至少还可以拔出你的枪！
You could at least have drawn your guns!
先听布奇说完 他有话要跟你说
Listen to Butch. He's trying to tell you something.
好吧 你们想干什么？
All right. What do you want?
有几件事情 我们想入伍 雷
A couple of things. We wanna enlist, Ray.
你知道 参军 就现在！去打西班牙人
You know, in the army. Right away! Go fight the Spanish.
噢 你疯了 你疯了
Oh, you're crazy. You are crazy.
你们两个都疯了！
You are both of you crazy!
他们应该把你们两个丢进监狱里各关上1000年！
They'd throw you in jail for a thousand years each!
来吧 圣丹斯 把我的脚捆起来
Come on, Sundance. Start trussing my feet.
来吧 你应该看过怎么做的 来吧！我可不想万一被别人看见我让你们进来
Here, you've seen these before. Come on! I'm not gonna take the chance someone saw you.
雷 我们是认真的
Ray, we're serious about this.
- 你们都是出名的通缉犯   - 我们不干了
- You are known outlaws. - We quit.
- 不干了！   - 是那样的 我们会的 不会太紧了吧？
- Quit! - That's the point, we would. Too tight?
没有 刚刚好 在最顶上那个抽屉里有手帕 你可以拿来堵住我的嘴
No, that's all right. There's hankies in the top drawer you can use to gag me.
噢 这能行的 这能行的 雷
Oh, this'd work. This'd work, Ray.
你相信我们 政府相信你 不管你对他们怎么说 他们都会相信的
You trust us and the government trusts you, so anything you tell them, they gotta believe it.
你这辈子还从没做过什么不老实的事吧 你什么人 都快60了？我们不干了
You've never done a dishonest thing in your life and what are you, pushing 60? We'd quit.
只要他们撤销对我们的所有指控 我们就会一直打到战争结束
They'd drop all the charges. We'd fight till the war is over.
- 他们甚至不用让我们当军官   - 这真算得上是提议
- They don't even have to make us officers. - That's some proposition.
我是说 他们忘掉这些年你们做的所有盗劫勾当？
I mean, they forget all about the years of thieving and robbing?
你们现在最想的 就是让你们参军
They take you into the army, which is what you want in the first place.
要是对你们这么说你们自己也会被吓到的 嗯？
There's something out there that scares you, huh?
现在太晚了 你们现在除了被打死早就没有那个机会了
It's too late. Shoulda let yourselves get killed a long time ago while you had the chance.
听着 你们或许是这个地区到目前为止悬赏最高的 可你们都不过是小通缉犯！
See, you may be the biggest thing ever hit this area, but you're still two-bit outlaws!
我从没见过比你更和善的人 或是拔枪比小子还快的
I never met a soul more affable than you, or faster than the Kid,
可你们不过是两个东躲西藏的小通缉犯 已经结束了！你们还不明白吗？
but you're still nothing but two-bit outlaws on the dodge. It's over! Don't you get that?
你们的时代已经结束了 你们都会被打死！你们能做的就是选择死在什么地方
Your times is over and you're gonna die bloody! And all you can do is choose where.
抱歉 我这把年纪说话越来越刻薄了
I'm sorry. I'm getting mean in my old age.
来吧！让我闭嘴吧 圣丹斯
Come on! Shut me up, Sundance.
啊 你在浪费你的时间
Ah, you're wasting your time.
- 他们在岩石路面上无法追踪我们   - 这话跟他们去说吧
- They can't track us over rock. - Tell them that.
他们开始让我感到紧张了
They're beginning to get on my nerves.
这都是些什么人？
Who are those guys?
你还记得那次你和我还有埃塔去丹佛夏季度假吗？
You remember the time you and me and Etta went to Denver that summer for a vacation?
很高兴你提起那个 真是个很重要的话题 想想我们现在的情势吧
Glad you brought that up. An important topic, considering our situation.
- 我们去赌钱的那天晚上 还记得吗？   - 我们在宾馆里吃晚饭
- The night we went gambling. Remember? - We had dinner at the hotel.
埃塔点了烧牛肉 我点了鸡 要是我能记起来你点的什么 我就是死了也会很高兴的！
Etta had roast beef and I had chicken. If I can remember what you had, I'll die a happy man!
- 你看那里   - 什么？
- Look out there. - What?
那天晚上我们同别的赌客谈话的时候 那人跟我们说了一个印第安人的事
We got to talking to some gambler that night and he told us about an Indian.
一个纯种的印第安人 只不过他给自己取了个英文名字 叫什么先生
A full-blooded Indian, except he called himself with an English name. Sir somebody.
- 罗德 巴尔的摩？   - 没错 据说他能追踪任何人
- Lord Baltimore? - That's right. And he could track anybody.
不管什么在地形 白天还是晚上
Over anything, day or night.
那么？
So?
那个趴在地上的家伙 我想应该就是他
The guy on the ground, I think it's him.
不 你说巴尔的摩在俄克拉荷马之外活动 他可是个地道的俄克拉荷马人
No, Baltimore works out of Oklahoma. He's strictly an Oklahoma man.
我不知道我们现在在什么地方 不过这里绝对不是他妈的俄克拉荷马
I don't know where we are, but it sure as hell isn't Oklahoma.
嗷 这不可能是他
Aw, it couldn't be him.
这不可能是他
It couldn't be him.
我想是吧
I guess.
不管他是谁 这家伙绝对是个人物
Whoever it is, it sure the hell is somebody.
该死！他们就不累吗？他们就不饿吗？
Dammit! Don't they get tired? Don't they get hungry?
- 他们当然会   - 那为什么他们还没慢下来？
- They gotta be. - Why don't they slow up?
该死 他们还能追得再快点儿 至少那也算是有点儿变化 他们甚至连队形都没乱
Hell, they could go faster. At least that'd be a change. They don't even break formation.
快想点儿办法！
Do something!
- 小子   - 什么？
- Kid? - What?
最好的警长是谁？
Who's the best lawman?
最好的？那种最好的？你是指最厉害的 还是最容易被收买的？
Best? How? You mean toughest, or easiest to bribe?
最厉害的
Toughest.
乔 勒弗斯
Joe Lefors.
绝对是他
Gotta be.
勒弗斯从不离开怀俄明 从来也没有 你知道的
Lefors never leaves Wyoming. Never. You know that.
他总是带着一顶白色的帽子
He always wears a white skimmer.
这么说你从他戴的白色草帽断定他是乔 勒弗斯
That's how you tell it's Joe Lefors cos he wears a white straw hat.
你看走在前面的那个家伙
Look at that guy out front.
呃 这都什么人啊？
Jeez, who are those guys?
快走！
Come on!
快走 笨蛋
On your feet, you dumbhead.
快走 离开这儿！快走！
Go on! Get outta here! Go on!
要是他们没有追着马去怎么办？
What if they don't follow the horse?
你脑袋那么聪明 布奇 你会想到办法的
You're the brains, Butch. You'll think of something.
该死！
Dammit!
我想现在出路就是 我们要么抵抗要么投降
The way I figure it, we can either fight or give.
- 要是我们投降 我们就得进监狱   - 我已经去过那儿了
- If we give, we go to jail. - I've been there already.
可要是我们抵抗 他们可以困住我们把我们饿死
But if we fight, they can stay right where they are and starve us out.
或是找到合适的位置 向我们开枪 甚至滚块石头下来砸死我们
Or go for position, shoot us. Might even get a rock slide started and get us that way.
他们还会做什么呢？
What else can they do?
他们可能会投降 不过我可不对那抱什么希望
They could surrender, but I wouldn't count on that.
他们一定会选择寻找合适的位置
They're going for position all right.
还是做好准备
Better get ready.
小子 下次我要说我们去类似波利维亚的地方 我们就去那种地方吧
Kid, the next time I say let's go someplace like Bolivia, let's go someplace like Bolivia.
下次吧...
Next time...
准备好了吗？
Ready?
不 我们跳下去
No, we'll jump.
- 就当是拼命赌一把吧   - 不 不会有问题的
- Like hell we will. - No, it'll be OK,
要是我们没有摔成烂泥 他们就再也追不上我们了
if we're not squished to death. They'll never follow us.
- 你怎么知道？   - 要你不是走投无路你会跳下去吗？
- How do you know? - Would you jump if you didn't have to?
- 就算我走投无路我也不会跳   - 噢 我们得跳 否则我们就死了
- I have to and I'm not gonna. - Well, we got to, otherwise we're dead.
他们只能原路返回
They'll just have to go back the same way they come.
- 就开一枪   - 得了
- Just one clear shot. - Come on.
- 我们得跳下去！   - 别管我
- We got to! - Get away from me.
- 为什么？   - 我要跟他们打！
- Why? - I wanna fight them!
- 他们会杀了我们的！   - 也许吧
- They'll kill us! - Maybe.
- 你想死吗？   - 那你呢？
- You wanna die? - Do you?
好吧 我先跳
All right. I'll jump first.
- 不   - 那你先跳
- No. - Then you jump first.
- 不 我说了   - 你怎么了？
- No, I said. - What's the matter?
我不会游泳！
I can't swim!
什么 你疯了吗？光跳下去说不定就已经死了！
Why, are you crazy? The fall will probably kill ya!
- 你这样会让我溺水的！   - 我办不到！我不会游泳！
- You're drowning me! - I can't help it! I can't swim!
- 小子 我会死的！你勒住我喉咙了！   - 我不会游泳！
- Kid, I'll kill ya! You're choking me! - I can't swim!
我告诉你 要是我溺水了 我发誓我会杀了你的！
I'm telling you, if I drown, I swear I'll kill you!
别再说我是个游泳高手
Never said I was a great swimmer.
你勒住我喉咙了！你勒住我喉咙了！
You're choking me! You're choking me!
你没必要勒住我！
You don't have to choke me!
小子 别勒住我的喉咙！
Kid, let go of my throat!
报纸上说他们打死你们了
The papers said they had you.
- 是勒弗斯吗？是他们说的吗？   - 乔 勒弗斯？我想是的
- Was it Lefors? Did they say? - Joe Lefors? I think so.
- 那他们的追踪者呢？   - 追踪者？
- And their tracker? - Tracker?
- 是罗德 巴尔的摩？   - 我想是的 报纸上都登了
- Was it Lord Baltimore? - I think so. The paper's inside.
你有准备够我们吃的吗？
You got enough to feed us?
你不知道我会准备的吗？
Don't you know I do?
- 他们说你们都死了   - 这又不是什么大事
- They said you were dead. - Don't make a big thing out of it.
不 还是当做大事吧
No, make a big thing out of it.
嘿！
Hey!
是巴尔的摩还有勒弗斯
It was Baltimore and Lefors.
什么？
What?
- 你知道还有谁吗？   - 谁？
- You know who else? - Who?
- 杰夫 卡尔还有乔治 海特   - 海特？
- Jeff Car, George Hiatt. - Hiatt?
TT 科勒尔
TT Kelliher.
呃 我们要没逃掉就死定了 你知道吗？
Jeez, we lucked out getting away. You know that?
可为什么这些人联手起来对付我们 嗯？
But why would these guys join up and take after us, though?
别管了 那样一伙人不会聚在一起很久的
Forget it. A bunch like that won't stay together long.
- 他们会的 要是哈里曼先生继续的话   - 谁？
- They will, if Mr Harriman has his way. - Who?
联合太平洋铁路公司的EH 哈里曼先生 你们选择对他下手把他惹火了
EH Harriman of the Union Pacific Railroad. He resents the way you've picked on him,
所以他派出了一列特别列车并雇了这些特殊的雇员
so he's outfitted a special train and hired special employees.
你们最近这两天都在躲避他们
You've spent the last two days avoiding them.
某种程度上这真是抬举你们了 要是你们能这么想的话
It's really sort of flattering, if you wanna think about it that way.
- 这一招看起来花的钱比我们抢的还要多   - 很显然他付得起
- A setup like that costs more than we took. - Apparently he can afford it.
那个疯子哈里曼
That crazy Harriman.
这交易太不划算了！
That's bad business!
要是我每次抢劫都是亏钱 你认为我还会这样干多久？
How long d'you think I'd stay in operation if every time I pulled a job it cost me money?
要是他把那笔钱给我让我别再抢劫他了 我就不会再抢他了！
If he'd pay me what he's spending to make me stop robbing him, I'd stop robbing him!
说不定你的每一份钱都是继承的遗产！
You probably inherited every penny you got!
- 富二代 他们都他妈懂什么？   - 你是说他们被终身雇佣了？
- Inherited guys. What the hell do they know? - You say they're hired permanent?
不 在他们杀掉你们之前
No. Just till they kill you.
这么说他们还在追着我们 布奇
That means they're still after us, Butch.
那样又要重演一遍了
And it's gonna be the same thing all over again.
他们会到这儿来的 迟早的事情
They'll show up here, sooner or later.
嘿 埃塔
Hey, Etta.
我再去给你拿点儿
I'll get you some more.
布奇同我已经都谈过了
Butch and me have been talking it all over.
不管该死的玻利维亚在什么地方 我们要去那儿
Wherever the hell Bolivia is, that's where we're off to.
嗯 等我们到了那儿我们会小心的干的 说不定我们只对那些小点儿的目标下手
Yeah, we'll go down there and play it safe. Maybe keep our hand in a little bit.
- 布奇能说一些西班牙语   - 我只要能看懂菜谱就OK了
- Butch speaks some Spanish. - I can wrestle with a menu OK.
你的西班牙语说得很好
And you speak it good.
要是能同一个女人一起去应该是个很好的掩护
It'd be good cover going with a woman.
不会有人会想到的
No one expects it.
我们路上会比较安全
We could travel safer.
我是说要是你想去的话 我不会拦着你
What I'm saying is if you wanna go, I won't stop you.
可要是你开始哭泣或让人心烦的话
But the minute you start to whine or make a nuisance,
不管我们在什么地方 我就会把你甩掉
I don't care where we are, I'm dumping you flat.
别说得真么好听 小子 跟她直说吧
Don't sugarcoat it like that, Kid. Tell her straight.
我已经26了 还是单身的学校老师 已经生活得最为煎熬了
I'm 26 and I'm single and a schoolteacher, and that's the bottom of the pit.
唯一能让我高兴的就是和你们在一起的时候
And the only excitement I've known is here with me now.
我要跟你们走 我不会抱怨的 我要替你们补袜子还替你们缝伤口
So I'll go with you and I won't whine, and I'll sew your socks and stitch your wounds,
你们要我做什么都可以 除了一件事
and I'll do anything you ask of me, except one thing.
我不要看到你们死
I won't watch you die.
要是你们不介意的话 我会想起那一幕的
I'll miss that scene, if you don't mind.
未来都是属于你的 你这辆破自行车！
The future's all yours, ya lousy bicycles!
往纽约哈林区
纽约旅行社
噢 你知道 这还算好的
Well, you know, it could be worse.
你的钱够你在玻利维亚花了 我看过了
You get a lot more for your money in Bolivia. I checked on it.
那儿有什么你会想要买的东西吗？
What could they have here that you could possibly wanna buy?
呃 玻利维亚可不都是这样
Jeez, all Bolivia can't look like this.
你怎知道？这可能是这整个国家里最漂亮的地方了
How do you know? This might be the garden spot of the whole country.
人们说不定旅行数百英里就是为了到这个我们正站着的地方来
People may travel hundreds of miles just to get to this spot where we're standing now.
这里也许就是玻利维亚的新泽西州的大西洋城
This might be the Atlantic City, New Jersey of all Bolivia.
我知道玻利维亚的事比你对大西洋城知道的还多 我可以这么说
I know a lot more about Bolivia than you know about Atlantic City, I can tell you that.
是吗 嗯？
You do, huh?
我就出生在那里
I was born there.
我出生在新泽西
I was born in New Jersey.
- 我在那里长大 因此...   - 你是从东部来的 我还不知道
- Brought up there. So... - You're from the East. I didn't know.
你不知道的事情还多着呢...
The total tonnage of what you don't know is enough to...
- 我不认为我们有达到什么目的   - 听着！
- I'm not sure we're accomplishing anything. - Listen!
你的工作就是支持我 要是没有我你就会饿死
Your job is to back me up, because you'd starve without me.
而 你 你的工作就是闭嘴！
And, you, yourjob is to shut up!
噢 等他抢劫完几家银行之后他就会感觉好多了
Well, he'll feel a lot better after he's robbed a couple of banks.
波利维亚！
Bolivia!
该死 这跟别的银行一样 慢慢走进去 仔细观察
Hell, it's just a bank like any other bank. Gotta move in slowly, check out everything.
- 别忘了...   - 别告诉我该怎么抢银行！我知道该怎么做！
- The thing to remember... - Don't tell me how to rob a bank! I know how!
伙计 你的额头看起来有些愁容不展啊 看起来沮丧极了 不是吗？
Boy, a few dark clouds appear on your horizon, you just go all to pieces, don't you?
上午好 先生们 有什么可以让我效劳的吗？有什么需要的话 请吩咐 我马上办
Buenos días, señores, Les puedo servir en algo? Ordenen, por favor, inmediatamente,
你们是要存钱吗？
Quieren hacer algún depósito?
如果您是想开户的话 请找收银员 会为您马上办理的
Si quieren abrir alguna cuenta, vean al cajero, Inmediatamente los atendemos,
先生？
Señor?
再见
Adiós,
这是抢劫
This is a robbery.
Esto es un robo,
这是抢劫
这是必须会背的行话
This is a unison recitation.
我才不背 他说他懂这该死的西班牙语！
I'm not doing this. He claimed he knew the damn language!
我们以前就讨论过这个了 你干这行需要掌握一些专业词汇
We've been over this before. Your line of work requires a specialized vocabulary.
- 我刚才紧张了 我忘记怎么说了 你打死我吧！   - 你最近尽是些烂主意！
- I got nervous. I forgot the words. Shoot me! - You've had worse ideas lately!
把手举起来
Raise your hands.
Las manos arriba,
举起来
Raise them.
Arriba,
你们所有人 都背靠墙站好
All of you, back against the wall.
你们所有人
Todos ustedes,
然后是...“马上”靠墙站好
and then..."arrísmense" a la pared,
把钱给我
Give me the money.
这样没用的 就算是花上一整夜我们也要让你学会
This is not going to work and we'll be up all night until you get this.
现在说 把钱给我
Now, give me the money.
话已经快到嘴边了 埃塔 我发誓
It's on the tip of my tongue, Etta. I swear it.
布奇 你还待在那儿想吗？
Butch, are you still thinking in there?
要不然该死的还能做什么？
What the hell else is there to do?
试试这句
Try this one.
保险箱在那儿？把它打开
Where is the safe? Open it.
在那儿？
Dónde es,,,?
这句太难了
That's a hard one.
箱子在哪里？打开！
Dónde está la caja? Ábrala!
非常好 布奇
That's very good, Butch.
你是个好老师 埃塔
You're a good teacher, Etta.
- 这是抢劫！   - 抢劫？
- Esto es un robo! - Un robo?
把手
Manos a,,,
Manos,,,
- 把手举起来！   - 他们已经举起来了！跳过这一句
- Manos arriba! - They got them up! Skip on down.
- 举起来！   - 跳过这一句！
- Arriba! - Skip on down!
- 你们所有人“马上”靠墙站好   - 他们已经都靠墙站着了!
- Todos ustedes "arrísmense" a la pared, - They're against the wall already!
箱子 啊 你这么聪明 你来念！
Dónde,,, Ah, you're so damn smart, you read it!
- 你干得很不错   - 你一点也帮不上忙
- Lot of good you did. - You didn't help.
你要没有小抄什么也干不好
You ain't any good without a crib sheet.
强盗！
Bandidos!
- 看在上帝的面上 别把钱丢了！   - 我不会的
- For God's sake, don't drop the money! - I won't!
- 我这就去把警长叫来   - 是啊 那样我们就完了！
- Voy a traer al comisario, - Sí, vamos!
- 你叫什么名字？   - 埃瓦里斯托
- Su nombre? - Evaristo,
埃瓦里斯托什么？
Evaristo qué?
警长 有两个男人在抢劫银行
Comandante, dos hombres acaban de asaltar el banco,
- 是什么人？   - 是两个美国人还有一个女孩儿
- Quiénes eran? - Dos yanquis y una muchacha,
他们抢走了我所有的钱还有我的枪
Se llevaron todo el dinero y mi pistola,
那我们走！来吧 上马！
Vamonos! Vengan ustedes, a los caballos!
这难道不是美好的景色吗？
Isn't that a pretty sight?
我们又重出江湖了 男孩儿还有女孩儿们 就跟过去一样
We're back in business, boys and girls, just like the old days.
美国抢匪
- 何塞！   - 什么事 先生
- Jose! - Sí, señor,
我们要留下来 逮住并干掉他
We should stay, get him and be done with it.
没错 可要是我们失败了呢？我们看见他带着两个人 可要是他带着20个人呢？
Yeah, but what if we lose? We saw him with two guys, but what if he's got 20?
- 你还不确定那就是勒弗斯   - 我的猜测绝对不会错的
- You don't know for sure it's Lefors. - I'm a hell of a guesser.
他在这里不能逮捕你们 这里是国外 也不能把你们带回去
He can't arrest you here. It's a foreign country. Or take you back.
他才不会把我们带回去 他只想在这里干掉我们
He's not gonna take anybody back. He wants to finish us here.
他会等着我们动手 然后就像之前那样追踪我们
He'll wait for us to pull ajob, then hunt us like before.
要是这次他没追到 他就会等到下一次我们动手 我们现在就了结了算了 没有别的办法
And if he misses us, he'll wait for the next job. Let's finish it now, one way or the other.
他在等我们动手 对吧？等我们动手？
He's gotta wait for us, right? To pull anotherjob?
嗯 要是我们不动手了呢？
Well, what if there isn't anotherjob?
我的意思是说 这样他就不能逮捕我们 也不能把我们从这里带走了
I mean, he can't arrest us and he can't take us outta here.
我们会把他逼疯的 我们就会永远躲过这个混蛋 我们要改邪归正了！
We'll drive him crazy. We'll outlast the bastard. We'll go straight!
那么说你们想找工作？
So you want jobs?
你们是从美国来的 你们正在找工作
You're from the US of A and you are seeking after employment.
噢 你们在玻利维亚找不出比这更偏僻的地方了 我得告诉你们
Well, you couldn't have picked a more out of the way place in all Bolivia, I'll tell you that.
感谢 耶稣
Gracias, Jesús,
在过去 要想为珀西工作的话你们还得等候 不过已经今非昔比了
Ordinarily, you've got to wait to work for Percy Garris, but this ain't ordinarily.
那太好了
Bingo.
- 你是说有工作？   - 是的 是有工作 这里有的是工作
- You mean there are jobs? - Yes, there are jobs. There are lots of jobs.
你们就不想知道是为什么吗？
Don't you wanna know why?
嗯 为什么？
Yeah. Why?
该死的
Dammy.
因为我不能保证会付你钱
Because I cannot promise to pay you.
你们就不想知道为什么吗？
Don't you wanna know why?
OK 为什么？
OK. Why?
都是因为抢匪的关系 公民们
On account of the payroll thieves, fellow citizens.
你也看见了 这周围所有的矿场的工资都是从拉巴斯运来的
You see, every mine around gets its payroll from La Paz.
而着周围所有的矿场的工资都被抢劫了
And every mine around gets its payroll held up.
有人说是玻利维亚的抢匪...
Some say it's the Bolivian bandits and...
还有人说是“美国抢匪”
some say that it's the "Bandidos Yanquis."
能给我看看吗？
Could I see that?
看起来很不错 你能打中什么吗？
Fairly nice-Iooking piece. Can you hit anything?
有时候吧
Sometimes.
打下那个
Hit that.
不 不 孩子 不 孩子 我只是想知道你会不会开枪
No, no, son. No, son. I just wanna know can you shoot.
把你的枪拿好...
Put your piece in your hand...
然后开枪
and shoot.
该死
Dammy.
我可以活动吗？
Can I move?
活动？你说该死的活动什么意思？
Move? What the hell you mean move?
- 我在活动的时候打得比较好   - 耶
- I'm better when I move. - Yeah.
噢 考虑到我已经别无选择 你就是我要找的人
Well, considering that I'm desperate and you are just what I'm looking for,
此外你们都是美国人 我们明天上午就开始吧
on top of which you stem from the US of A, we start tomorrow morning.
- 你的意思是我们得到工作了？   - 工资押运
- You mean we gotjobs? - Payroll guard.
该死
Dammy.
让我们开始工作吧！
Vámonos a trabajar!
嘿 卡斯托！卡斯托！
Hey, Chusto! Chusto!
噢 你忘了派克的小甜甜贝琪了吗？
Oh, don't you remember sweet Betsy from Pike?
带着她的爱穿行于高耸的山脉 就好像
Crossed the high mountains with her lover, like
两头套着犁木的牛还有一只汪汪叫的大狗
Two yoke of oxen and a big yeller dog
一只上海大公鸡还有一只斑点猪
A tall Shanghai rooster and one spotted hog
Toodle-dang hoodie aye-doh, toodle-dang hoodie ay
上海公鸡跑了而牛也全都死了
The Shanghai ran off and the cattle all died
那天早上的最后一块熏肉...
Last piece of bacon that morning...
我认为他们就躲在前面的树林里
I think they're in the trees up ahead.
- 就在左边的灌木丛里   - 他们就在前面的树林里！
- In the bushes on the left. - They're in the trees up ahead!
你去检查树林 我去检查灌木丛
You take the trees, I'll take the bushes.
你们两个新手能不能别闹了！
Will you two beginners cut it out!
噢 我们只是想侦查一下有没有埋伏 伽里斯先生
Well, we're just trying to spot an ambush, Mr Garris.
蠢货
Morons.
我的队伍里有两个蠢货
I've got morons on my team.
在下山的时候是不会有人打劫我们的！
Nobody is going to rob us going down the mountain!
我们在下山的时候身上就没有钱！
We have got no money going down the mountain!
那要等到我们拿了钱 回来的时候
When we have got the money, on the way back,
那时候才需要你们卖力
then you can sweat.
说的没错
Bingo.
我们在6月份的时候在这里进行过抢劫 对吧？
We hit this place in June, didn't we?
琼斯！
Jones!
过来帮我一下
Give me a hand over here.
我是说？史密斯还是琼斯？
Who am I? Smith or Jones?
过去吧！
Live!
还要再过半个小时我们才需要开始加强注意
'Bout a half-hour more and we can start to worry.
在我们到达上面那个山口之前 在到那儿之前我们都不会有事的
As soon as we get to the pass up there. We'll be all right till then.
- 他们可能在这里埋伏   - 不可能 上面那儿更容易隐蔽
- They might try something here. - Nah. Better cover up there.
你们别那么紧张 伙计们 你们得适应玻利维亚的工作方式
You got to relax, you fellas. You got to get used to Bolivian ways.
你们得放松些 该死！
You got to go easy. Dammy!
就像我这样
Like I do.
不过 你们可能认为我疯了 可我没有
Course, you probably think I'm crazy, but I'm not.
没错 我活得很精彩
Bingo. I'm colorful.
要是你们在玻利维亚生活上10年你们也会这样的 你们也会活得很精彩
That's what happens when you live ten years alone in Bolivia. You get colorful.
他们在哪里？
Where are they?
我看不到他们
I can't see them.
我们离开这儿！
Let's get outta here!
让他们把钱放下离开
Tell them to leave the money and go.
让他们把“田” 钱...
Dejen el "dinoro",,, dinero and...
离开
y váyanse,
让我们把钱全都放下？
Que dejemos el dinero y nos vayamos?
告诉他们我们是被雇来把钱带回去的 这是我们的工作！
Tell them we were hired to take it back. It's ourjob!
告诉他们钱不是我们的
Tell them the money isn't ours.
这些钱 不是我们的
El dinero,,, no es nuestro,
不 不是你们的 现在它是我们的
No, ya no es de ustedes, Ahora es de nosotros,
很显然！
Claro!
我们再跟他们说一遍 这是我们的工作 这些钱不是我们的
We'll try telling them again. It's ourjob. The money isn't ours.
这笔钱不是我们的
El dinero no es nuestro,
- 我们需要它   - 我们也需要它
- Lo necesitamos, - También nosotros lo necesitamos,
- 你觉得怎么样？   - 不太顺利
- What do you think? - Not so good.
你能对付右边的那两个吗？
Can you take the two on the right?
小子 有件事我想应该让你知道 我之前还从未向人开过枪
Kid, there's something I think I oughta tell ya. I never shot anybody before.
偏在这种要命的时候告诉我这个
One hell of a time to tell me.
我们最好还是散开 因为他们可能会想杀了我们
Vale más que se hagan a un lado, porque a lo mejor éstos nos matan,
试着对付右边的那两个 瞄准胸口 那样就算你没打中 你总会打中什么的
Try for the two on the right. Aim dead center. That way if you miss, you still hit something.
- 快走！   - 什么？
- Go! - Qué?
- 拜托你们！   - 什么？
- Please! - Qué?
- 拜托   - 拜托！
- Por favor, - Por favor!
噢 我们已经改邪归正了
Well, we've gone straight.
我们正在试着改邪归正
What'll we try now.
要知道 还有别的改邪归正的办法
There are other ways of going straight, you know.
还有别的改邪归正的办法
There are other ways of going straight.
可以搞农场
There's farming.
我们可以买一块地
We could buy a place.
我不知道该怎么经营农场
I don't know how to farm.
那牧场呢 嗯？
What about a ranch, then?
最后一次我们试着在一个牧场工作是在偷牛的时候了
The last time we tried a ranch was during our rustling days.
那时候起我们就不擅长放牧 那很艰难 我们已经老了
And even then we weren't much good at it. It's hard. Hours are brutal.
不 要经营牧场你得是个年轻小子才行
No, you gotta be a kid to start a ranch.
嘿
Hey.
我可能比你先一步回去
I might go back ahead of you.
你是说回家？
You mean home?
我已经考虑过了
I was thinking of it.
不管你怎么想 埃塔
Whatever you want, Etta.
也许我会离开的
Maybe I'll go.
嘿
Hey.
埃塔想可能比我们先回去
Etta's thinking of maybe going home ahead of us.
随便她想什么
Whatever she wants.
那 我就离开了
I'll go, then.
把手举起来！
Manos arriba!
- 你抢了多少？   - 这真不值得 阿尔博卡矿场
- How much you got? - It's hardly worth it. Alpoca Mine.
- 我告诉你 别在丛林里动手了   - 你就快变成个老太婆了
- I tell you, no more jungle work for me. - You're getting to be an old maid.
把你老太婆的唠叨话留给你自己吧 要是你不介意的话
Keep your old-maid remarks to yourself, if you don't mind.
我可以在城里还有山上抢劫 不过从今天起我绝对不在丛林里抢劫！
I'll work in the city and mountains, but from now on jungle work is out!
美国抢匪？
Bandidos Yanquis?
让他们安静
Tell them to be quiet.
- 该怎么说？   - 安静
- What's the word? - Quietos,
安静！
Quietos!
我告诉你 在丛林里抢钱更容易隐蔽
I tell you, the jungle's a better cover for payrolls.
小子 我有权保留我的看法 在我看来丛林里到处都是蛇
Kid, I got a right to my opinion, and in my opinion there are snakes in the jungle.
我可不想在有蛇的地方抢钱
I don't work around snakes.
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
我不知道 我想是 圣 文森特吧
I don't know. San Vicente, I think.
- 要吃什么？   - 是的 先生
- Comer? - Sí, señor, Pasen,
胡安！过来 把马牵走
Juan! Ven, Llévate los caballos,
我不喜欢丛林或是沼泽 我不喜欢有蛇 我对在晚上工作倒不在意
I don't enjoy jungles or swamps. I don't like snakes. I don't much care for night work.
混蛋 混蛋 混蛋
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
队长！队长！
Capitán! Capitán!
队长 广场上有一只阿尔博卡矿场的骡子
Capitán, allí en la plaza hay una mula de las minas de Alpoca,
- 是阿尔博卡矿场的？   - 是的 是的
- De las minas de Alpoca? - Sí, sí,
是两个人带来的 他们正在我爸爸的餐馆里吃饭
Allí está, dos hombres la acaban de traer, están comiendo en el restorán de mi papá,
味道炖得相当好 好到你们会舔手指
El guisado está delicioso, Para chuparse los dedos,
这是本店的特色菜
Es la especialidad de la casa,
希望你们不要不好意思 有什么需要就告诉我 我随时为你们服务
Se quieren más no tengan pena y díganmelo, Yo estoy aquí para servirles,
像你们这样高贵的先生来我很高兴
Agradezco la visita de tan distinguidos caballeros,
非常感谢 随时为你们服务
Muchas gracias, Para servirles,
- 非常感谢   - 是的
- Muchas gracias, - Sí,
这家店的特色菜居然还在动啊！
The specialty of the house and it's still moving!
噢 就这么定了 这地方我再也不会来了
Well, that settles it. This place gets no more of my business.
- 嘿   - 什么事？
- Hey. - What?
你怎么想？
What do you think?
我打赌只有一个人
I bet it's just one guy.
你总是没事没事的你就不觉得烦吗？
Don't you get sick of being right all the time?
装子弹
Reloading.
我就只有这么多
That's all I got.
要是我们不能从骡子身上拿点儿子弹我们很快就没子弹了
We're gonna run out unless we can get to that mule and get some more.
我去
I'll go.
这不是逞英雄的时候 我会让你去
This is no time for bravery. I'll let you.
子弹装好了
Loaded.
该死！必须得是我去
Hell! I'm the one that has to go.
为什么是你？
Why you?
因为我永远也掩护不了你 你可以掩护我
Cos I could never give you cover. You can cover me.
你也知道我说的是对的 对吧？
You can see I'm right, can't you?
- 你去   - 是啊 为什么我总是这么聪明得要死？
- You go. - Yeah, why am I always so damned smart?
行了 把你的枪给我
Here. Gimme your gun.
OK 去吧！
OK. Go!
OK！
OK!
去吧！
Go!
这...你也管这叫掩护？
Is... is that what you call giving cover?
你管这就叫跑吗？
Is that what you call running?
要是我...之前知道你这么慢吞吞的...
If I... knew you were gonna stroll...
你永远都打不好枪 甚至连初学者都算不上
You never could shoot, not from the very beginning.
你就只会嘴皮子！
And you are all mouth!
长官 军队赶来了
Jefe, ya llegó el ejército,
上校！
Mi capitán!
- 他们在哪里？   - 就在广场上
- Dónde están? - Allí en la plaza,
- 有多少人？   - 两名男子
- Cuántos hombres son? - Dos hombres,
- 两名？   - 上校
- Dos? - Mi capitán,,,
- 两名？   - 美国抢匪
- Dos? - Bandidos Yanquis,
- 美国抢匪 嗯？   - 是的 上校
- Bandidos Yanquis, eh? - Sí, mi capitán,
瑞可中士！让中尉带20个人
Sargento Rico! Desmonte a veinte hombres y que vengan con el teniente,
中士！从屋顶上把周围都包围起来 等我的命令
Sargento! Rodeen el zócalo, y suban hacia la azotea y espérenme,
分散包围起来！出发！
Media vuelta en el lugar! AI frente!
- 我想到一个我们之后该去的好地方   - 我不想听
- I got a great idea where we should go next. - I don't wanna hear it.
- 等我告诉你你就会改变主意的   - 闭嘴！
- You'll change your mind when I tell ya. - Shut up!
- OK OK   - 就是你的好主意让我们变成这样的...
- OK, OK. - Your great ideas got us here...
- 那就算了！   - 我再也不想听到你的什么主意了
- Forget it! - I never wanna hear another of your ideas.
- 好吧   - OK
- All right. - OK.
澳大利亚
Australia.
我想 你也许私下也想知道 那我就告诉你吧
I figured, secretly you wanted to know, so I told you.
澳大利亚
Australia.
- 那就是你的好主意？   - 噢 伙计 这是我最近...做出的长远打算
- That's your great idea? - Oh, boy, it's the latest in... in a long line.
- 澳大利亚可没这儿好   - 那是你所知道的而已
- Australia's no better than here. - That's all you know.
- 举个例子...   - 在澳大利亚他们说英语！
- Name me one thing... - They speak English in Australia!
- 是吗？   - 是的 聪明的家伙 那样我们就不会被认出是外国人了
- They do? - Yeah, smart guy. We wouldn't be foreigners.
澳大利亚有很多马 天呐 那儿离这里有好几千英里远 我们可以藏在那儿
They got horses in Australia. Hell, they got thousands of miles we could hide out in.
阳光 沙滩 你可还以学游泳
Good climate, beaches. You could learn to swim.
不！游泳不重要
No! Swimming isn't important.
那里的银行怎么样？
What about the banks?
太容易得手了 相当容易 又熟又丰满
They're easy. Easy, ripe and luscious.
你说的是银行还是女人？
The banks or the women?
噢 只要你抢了银行 也就有了女人！
Well, once you got one, you got the other!
- 就是路途遥远   - 你什么都要求十全十美！
- It's a long way though. - Everything's gotta be perfect with you!
我只是不想等到了才发现原来那儿糟透了 就这样
I just don't wanna get there and find out it stinks, that's all.
至少考虑一下吧
At least think about it.
好吧
All right.
我会考虑的
I'll think about it.
嘿
Hey.
等我们出去 上了马
When we get outside, when we get to the horses,
只要记住一件事
just remember one thing.
- 嘿 等等   - 怎么了？
- Hey, wait a minute. - What?
你没看见有勒弗斯吧 对吧？
You didn't see Lefors out there, did you?
勒弗斯
Lefors?
没有
No.
噢 那就好
Oh, good.
有一会儿我还以为我们遇到大麻烦了
For a moment there I thought we were in trouble.
开火！
Fuego!